# Kirill Shaplyko

#### **CONTACT**

Email: k.shaplyko@gmail.com

Skype: k.shaplyko

Phone: +66 61 576 13 50, +375 336 37 60 90

Github: Baltazore

LinkedIn: Kirill Shaplyko

Twitter: \_baltazore

#### **OVERVIEW**

I am a web developer with extensive knowledge and experience using Ruby and Javascript. My most recent experience has been as a full stack web developer at mobile advertising startup.

You can find some of my work on Github profile. My recent technological interests and passions include the ReactJS and Flux, AngularJS/EmberJS front-end javascript framework, and experimenting with writing back-end services in Go and Elixir.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### GameHouse

Software Developer, 2013 - current, Remote

- ► Full stack engineer responsible for development application using Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, MongoDB, Redis, AngularJS.
- Working on the deployments tasks. Learning Ansible and Docker for building container based hosts.
- ► Developing the advertisement platform for the mobile devices.
- ► Brainstorm and prototype the new approach for some parts of the application.
- Writing specs and cucumber scenarios for integration tests for our API endpoints.

#### RubyRoid Labs

Software Developer, 2013 - 2014, Remote

- ► Full stack engineer responsible for development application using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Redis, AngularJS, Elasticsearch.
- ► Document generation system. The project includes document generation, task management for Police Department, Hospitals, ect.

#### Itransition

Ruby on Rails Developer, 2012-2013, Minsk, Belarus

Mobile advertising platform for back-end, front-end and mobile clients API for iOS and Android. The project is intended to increase sales for businesses by providing discounts.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Redis, Sidekiq, Faye, Pushover.

► Online auction system. Full auction workflow support (from creating to send notification about winnign beds). Dealing with admin panel, server back-end for real-time bid system.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Redis, MySQL, Faye, MongoDB, Rescue

► Social Media Aggregation System. It aggregates data by keywords from Facebook, Twitter, Sysomos (15+ servises), Google News, Google Blogs, Youtube, Google Images and Vocus (Print media and Blogspot). Dealing with main aggregation gateways, alert system (sms, email), report system (pdf, plain text, html).

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Facebook API, Twitter API, Klout API, Elasticsearch

# **EDUCATION**

### Belarussian State of Informatics and Radioelectronics

B.S. in Computer Science, May 2014

## **TECHNOLOGY FOCUS**

Programming Languages: Ruby, Javascript, SQL, HTML5, CSS

Web Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Sintra, Rack, Node.js

Frontend Web Frameworks: ReactJS and Flux, AngularJS, EmberJS, jQuery, jQuery UI, Twitter Boot-

strap(2,3), Zurb Foundation(3, 4, 5)

DevOps: AWS (EC2, S3, Route53), Heroku, Chef, Ansible, Capistrano

Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, Fedora, and CoreOS), Mac OS X, Windows

Programming Editors/IDEs: vim, emacs, tmux, JetBrains RubyMine

Source Code Control: Git, Mercurial, Subversion

**Databases:** PostgreSQL 8/9, MySQL 4/5, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch **Content Management Systems/E-commerce:a** Spree, RefineryCMS

Other technologies: AMQP (RabbitMQ), Resque, Sidekiq